thank you it's moments like these John
kyaku will miss when he goes to jail
sometime soon he'll be told a cell is
available and his sentence can begin
he'll leave his wife and five children
the former CIA man pled guilty to
sending the name of another covert CIA
officer to a reporter that's against the
law he thought the man had retired and
could be interviewed he hadn't a plead
deal means he'll serve 2 and 1/2 years
did I commit that crime yes I did
I didn't have any intent to commit a
crime I didn't have any intent to harm
this individual John Kaku is the first
current or former CIA officer to be
convicted of the offense he was also the
first current or former CIA officer to
confirm prisoners were being
waterboarded tortured after the 9/11
attacks he believes his conviction is
politically motivated the only person
who's going to prison for having
anything related to do with the torture
regime is the guy who blew the whistle
on the torture the torturers aren't
going to prison the people who ordered
or conceived of the torture aren't going
to prison the US attorney that
prosecuted the case says the government
has a vital interest in protecting the
identities of those involved in covert
operations leaks of highly sensitive
closely held and classified information
compromise National Security and can put
individual lives in danger one
intelligence historian says it's simple
kyaku broke the law here's a man who
after 15 years in the CI Pro should have
known that you know there are certain
barriers Beyond which you know you
cannot go without risking uh life and
limb and U and he got caught Barack
Obama's White House has been accused of
leaking sensitive information when it
makes them look good for example on the
killing of AMA Bin Laden John kaku's
supporters say the administration wants
to shut down anything that is a negative
I think the lesson is it it chills
whistleblowers from telling the truth um
if you embarrass the government you will
be put under Criminal investigation if
you expose the war crimes of the
government you will be criminally
prosecuted and sent to jail John kyaku
is now facing legal bills of more than
half a million dollars while in jail
he'll miss birthdays christenings and
anniversaries he says he never intended
to damage National Security and believes
he didn't and insists if he hadn't
revealed details of the US torture
program he wouldn't now be going to jail
Alan Fischer Al jazer Arlington Virginia